Jonathan Prieto-Cubides

+57 301-4640435

CR 45 No. 68 Sur 36 Sabaneta, Antioquia

Bogotá, Cundinamarca

jprieto9@eafit.edu.co

CR 73 No. 51 14 http://www.github.com/jonaprieto

Date of Birth: 1991-04-18

Gender: Male

Citizenship: Colombia

Current Profession: Research Assistant

Ph.D Research Fellow in the Department of Informatics at University of Bergen in Norway. I'm interested

in mathematics for computer science. This includes type theory, logic and algorithms, category theory and related fields. I'm very willing to explore new fields and computer systems to formalise mathematics.

Research Experience

2018-present **Research Fellow**

University of Bergen. ICT Research Group. PUT.. Bergen, Norway

• Type Theory, Functional Programming

2016-2017

Young Research Assistant

EAFIT University. Logic and Computation Research Group. Medellín, Colombia

• Logic, Type Theory, Agda, Functional Programming

2013-2015

Young Researcher

Observatorio de Restitución y Regulación de Derechos de la Propiedad Agraria. Bogotá, Colombia

• Text Data Mining, Machine Learning, Algorithms, Functional Programming

Teaching Experience

2011-2014

Young Lecturer

Universidad Sergio Arboleda. Bogotá, Colombia

• Algorithms I 2011-2012, 2014

· Algorithms II 2011-2012, 2014

• Discrete Mathematics 2014

• Seminar of Competitive Programming 2014-2015

2016-II

Engineering

Instituto Tecnológico Metropolitano. Medellín, Colombia

• Linear Algebra

• Linear Programming and Algebra

Education

Master in Applied Mathematics

2016-present

(2 years)

EAFIT University. Medellín, Colombia.

Emphasis in Logic, Type Theory, and Functional Programming.

Thesis Title. Proof Recontruction Advisory. PhD. Andrés Sicard-Ramírez

2007-2013

Bachelor in Mathematics

(5 years)

Sergio Arboleda University. Bogotá, Colombia.

Emphasis in Computer Science

Thesis Title. An Introduction to Elliptic Curves

Advisory. PhD. Hermes Jackson

Publications

• Prieto-Cubides J., Argoty Camilo. *Dealing with Missing Data using a Selection Algorithm on Rough Sets.* 2017. International Journal of Computational Intelligence Systems. (Submitted)

Open-Source Projects

Haskell, Agda

Athena

http://github.com/jonaprieto/athena

Athena is a Haskell program that translates proofs given by Metis Prover in TSTP format to Agda code. This work was present in the Agda Implementors' Meeting XXV at Chalmers University.

Agda

Agda-Prop

http://github.com/jonaprieto/agda-prop

Agda library to work with Classical Propositional Logic using a deep embedding. Natural deductions Proofs for around seventy theorems.

Agda

Agda-Metis

http://github.com/jonaprieto/agda-metis

This library aims to provide the necessary functions and theorems for Athena to reconstruct proofs found by the automatic theorem prover, Metis.

Haskell

OnlineATPs

http://github.com/jonaprieto/online-atps

OnlineATPs is a command-line client for TPTP World. We can use an online ATP as it would be running locally. Indeed, SystemOnTPTP has available more than forty automatic theorem provers and we take avantage of all.

Latex

Curriculum-Vitae

http://github.com/jonaprieto/curriculum-vitae

This document was generated using this project. It makes easier maintain your Resume using LaTeX and Pandoc.

Python

PonyWhoosh

http://github.com/jonaprieto/ponywhoosh

Integration between the Whoosh search engine and PonyORM, this library makes your database full-text searchable

Python

Flask-PonyWhoosh

http://github.com/jonaprieto/flask-ponywhoosh

A web search engine for flask using PonyORM and Whoosh.

Private Projects

Mathematica

Poirot

Sergio Arboleda University, IEPRI, COLCIENCIAS

Poirot is a text search, a package, and analysis platform programmed in Mathematica®, designed for retrieval, analysis and systematization of large textual data (in the order of tens of thousands of files). Poirot is tailored for the needs of qualitative researchers, journalists, and state officials (in the judiciary, for example), that need to find specific textual bits in big masses of unstructured text.

Languages

- English B2
- · Spanish Native speaker

Achievements

- Scholarship. Agda Implementors' Meeting XXV at Chalmers University. Gotenburg, Sweden.
- Scholarship to study the master program in applied mathematics at EAFIT University
- Financial support to study mathematics at Sergio Arboleda University
- Member of the the program for talent young of high school. Sergio Arboleda University
- ACM-ICPC 2013 Regional Programing Contest. 9th Place, WTF Team
- ACM-ICPC 2013 National Programing Contest. 11th Place. WTF Team
- Honor mention. Colombian Math Contest 2010
- · Scholarship. Symposium ANTS X. San Diego, California. EEUU
- Early promotion at high school. 5th grade to 6th grade
- · Early promotion at high school. 7th grade to 8th grade
- Honors Academic Excellence, 10 and 11 degree in the school
- · National high school qualification exam ICFES. 4th place/group
- McDonald's drawing contest for schools. 1th Place 1997

References

- Phd. Andrés Sicard-Ramírez. asr@eafit.edu.co. Computer Science. EAFIT University
- Phd(c). Paola Lizarralde-Bejarano. dlizarra@eafit.edu.co. Mathematics. EAFIT University
- Phd. Camilo Argoty. argoty7@gmail.com. Mathematics. Sergio Arboleda University
- Phd. Esteban Hernández. Computer Science. eshernan@gmail.com Universidad Distrital de Bogotá.